CTE stands for Career Technical Education
and it differs from a traditional academic teaching credential
in several ways.
A CTE credential authorizes you to teach
within a specific subject area,
because you have a depth
and breadth of experience
as a working professional
in that field.
The courses that you would then be eligible
to teach with the CTE would be designated as
Career Technical, Vocational, or Trade courses
by the district in which you get hired.
Some basic requirements to earn a CTE credential
in arts/media/entertainment include:
having a high school diploma
and verification from employers
that you have at least three years of work experience
directly related to arts, media, and entertainment.
That's at least 1000 hours each year for three years.
What's unique about this credential is
you don't have to enroll
in a multi-year
university program.
You can pursue it
through your county office
of education,
university extensions,
and other continuing education programs.
With a preliminary CTE,
you can even work
towards your credential
while you're teaching
in a classroom.
And typically,
those with a CTE credential continue
to pursue their arts practice
and stay active
in their creative field.
There are other details
outlined in this website,
but the most important point
to remember is that
your experience, your knowledge, insight,
and skills from working
in the field of arts,
media, and entertainment
are requirements
for earning that CTE credential,
and they're also what distinguish you and
make you eligible to teach.